{"name": "62E 2010-12", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. The table below shows the linear relationship between x and y.What is the value of k ?", "choices": {"A": "-4", "B": "-2", "C": "-1", "D": "1", "E": "2"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. The range of normal monthly average temperatures in Fairbanks, Alaska, is from -13\u00b0F (in January) to 62\u00b0F (in July). How far apart, in degrees Fahrenheit, are these 2 monthly average temperatures?", "choices": {"A": "13\u00b0F", "B": "49\u00b0F", "C": "51\u00b0F", "D": "62\u00b0F", "E": "75\u00b0F"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. One morning, 3 elementary school students who walk to school together compared the number of marbles each of them had. Tina had 7 more marbles than Carlos, and Carlos had twice as many marbles as Jimmy, If Jimmy had j marbles, how many marbles did Tina have?", "choices": {"A": "j + 7", "B": "2j + 7", "C": "3j + 7", "D": "9j", "E": "2(j + 7)"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. Use the following information to answer questions 4-5.Clare decides to make a poodle skirt for her daughter Michaela for the 1950s dance at school next month. She found a scale drawing of a poodle skirt in a craft magazine and will use the drawing as a guide in making Michaela's skirt. On the scale drawing, which is shown below, 1 inch represents 1 foot.4. Clare finds that the radius of the skirt in the drawing measures  inches. What is the actual skirt's radius, in inches ?", "choices": {"A": "24", "B": "25", "C": "26", "D": "28", "E": "30"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. Use the following information to answer questions 4-5.Clare decides to make a poodle skirt for her daughter Michaela for the 1950s dance at school next month. She found a scale drawing of a poodle skirt in a craft magazine and will use the drawing as a guide in making Michaela's skirt. On the scale drawing, which is shown below, 1 inch represents 1 foot.Clare purchases  square yards of gray felt for the skirt at the fabric store. This gray felt cost $15.00. What is the cost per square yard of the felt ?", "choices": {"A": " $2.00", "B": "$3.00", "C": "$4.00", "D": "$4.50", "E": "$5.00"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. For the triangle below, a = 65. What is the value of b ?", "choices": {"A": "65", "B": "50", "C": "35", "D": "25", "E": "15"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. A spinner with 3 sectors is shown in the figure below. The measures of the central angles of the red, white, and blue sectors, in that order, are in the ratio 2 : 3 : 4. If the spinner is fair, what is the probability that the arrow stops in the red sector?(Note: Assume the arrow stops in a sector and not on a line. )", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. The triangles below are congruent, with \u25b3ABC \u224c \u0394DEF. The following lengths are given in centimeters: AB = x + 1, AC = x, BC = x + 2, and DF = 3x - 8. What is the value of x ?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "", "C": "4", "D": "", "E": "5"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. For the function h(x) = -16x2 + 10x + 300, the value of h(4) is:", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "84", "C": "212", "D": "468", "E": "596"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. What is the value of x + y(3 - x) when x= -5 and y = 3 ?", "choices": {"A": "-16", "B": "-11", "C": "9", "D": "11", "E": "19"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. Some students are going to Dallas on a school trip. The distance from their school to Dallas is 200 miles. The driver of the van carrying the students is told to allow 1 hour more than the time it would take to travel the 200 miles at 60 mph. About how much time should the driver allow for this trip to Dallas?", "choices": {"A": "2 hours 20 minutes", "B": "2 hours 40 minutes", "C": "3 hours 20 minutes", "D": "3 hours 40 minutes", "E": "4 hours 20 minutes"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. Of the 465 sophomores at Eastside High School, exactly  are taking French \u2161 or Chemistry \u2160 or both. There are 40 sophomores taking French II but not Chemistry I, and 60 sophomores taking Chemistry I but not French II. How many sophomores are taking both French II and Chemistry I?", "choices": {"A": "55", "B": "95", "C": "100", "D": "115", "E": "155"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. On May 1, Sugi and Deena started their own business servicing computers. The tatle below shows the number of clients they had during the months of May through August.Sugi and Deena assume that the number of clients they have each month will continue to double each month. One of the following graphs models the number of clients they will have each month according to their data and their assumption. Which one is it ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. Jean is going on a business trip and has packed 4 skirts, 5 blouses, and 3 jackets, An acceptable outfit consists of 1 skirt, 1 blouse, and 1 jacket from the clothing she packed. How many different acceptable outfits are possible from the skirts, blouses, and jackets Jean has packed?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "4", "C": "5", "D": "12", "E": "60"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15.  For all x \u2260 0,  = ?", "choices": {"A": "x", "B": "x3", "C": "x4", "D": "x7", "E": "x14"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. A certain imaginary country has units of measure such that 4 gogans make 1 milchkin, 2 milchkins make 1 choppin, and 2 choppins make 1 pezan. What fraction of a pezan is a gogan?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. Which of the 3 numbers listed below is the least and which is the greatest?8.3 x 103, 2.3 x 10-5, 1.2 x 104   least            greatest", "choices": {"A": "1.2 \u00d7 104        8.3 \u00d7 103", "B": "1.2 \u00d7 104        2.3 \u00d7 10-5", "C": "2.3 \u00d7 10-5        1.2 \u00d7 104", "D": "2.3 \u00d7 10-5        8.3 \u00d7 103", "E": "8.3 \u00d7 103        1.2 \u00d7 104"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. The equation 3x + B = 30 is equivalent to the equation x = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "10 - B", "D": "30 - B", "E": "30 - "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. (2a + b) - 3(a - b) - (b + a) is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "-2a + 3b", "B": "-2a + b", "C": "-3b", "D": "-b", "E": "3b"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. In North Ridge, all the streets run east-west or north-south from one edge of town to the opposite edge of town. North Ridge is mapped onto a standard (x, y) coordinate plane where each coordinate unit represents 1 block. Charles lives at the corner (5, 6). Hortensia lives at the corner (1, 3). What is the minimum number of blocks Hortensia can walk to reach Charles's home, walking only along the streets of North Ridge?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "3", "C": "5", "D": "7", "E": "15"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. A rectangular garden is to be 3 times as long as it is wide and is to be fenced on all 4 sides using 32 feet of fencing. What are the maximum possible dimensions, in feet, for the garden?", "choices": {"A": "8 by 4", "B": " by ", "C": "12 by 4", "D": "24 by 8", "E": "96 by 32"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. In the figure below, \u0394ABC is an equilateral triangle, and BD is perpendicular to AB. Also, AT, which intersects BD at E, is the bisector of \u2220BAC. What is the measure of \u2220TEB ?", "choices": {"A": "60\u00b0", "B": "75\u00b0", "C": "90\u00b0", "D": "120\u00b0", "E": "135\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. If  + 7 = -21, then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "-56", "B": "-28", "C": "-14", "D": "-7", "E": "14"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. In the figure below, E, F, G, and H are collinear; GH = 2EF; and \u0394DEF and \u0394DGH are isosceles triangles with bases EF and GH, respectively. What is the ratio of the area, in square units, of \u0394DGH to that of \u0394DEF ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "3 : 2", "C": "", "D": "2 : 1", "E": "3 : 1"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. When 5 consecutive integers are added together and the sum is then multiplied by 5, the result is 225. Which of the following is the largest of the 5 consecutive integers?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "7", "C": "9", "D": "11", "E": "13"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. Use the following information to answer questions 26-29.At registration for the first semester, the 1,500 students at Abraham Lincoln High School selected the primary mode of transportation each planned to use to get to school during the semester. The circle graph below shows the distribution of students who selected the various modes of transportation.      About how many of the students selected \"riding in a school bus\" ?", "choices": {"A": "38", "B": "300", "C": "325", "D": "375", "E": "1,125"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. Use the following information to answer questions 26-29.At registration for the first semester, the 1,500 students at Abraham Lincoln High School selected the primary mode of transportation each planned to use to get to school during the semester. The circle graph below shows the distribution of students who selected the various modes of transportation.      Gina wants to duplicate this circle graph. Which of the following is closest to the measure of the central angle of the \"walking\" sector?", "choices": {"A": "10\u00b0", "B": "15\u00b0", "C": "18\u00b0", "D": "30\u00b0", "E": "36\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Use the following information to answer questions 26-29.At registration for the first semester, the 1,500 students at Abraham Lincoln High School selected the primary mode of transportation each planned to use to get to school during the semester. The circle graph below shows the distribution of students who selected the various modes of transportation.      A student who parks at school must have a parking permit for the car he or she drives. For students who drive for a car pool, the permit costs $3. For students who drive alone, the permit costs $15.Before registration began, the school office had sold 165 student parking permits, 110 for car pools. What was the average cost paid for these 165 student parking permits?", "choices": {"A": "$6", "B": "$7", "C": "$9", "D": "$10", "E": "$11"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. Use the following information to answer questions 26-29.At registration for the first semester, the 1,500 students at Abraham Lincoln High School selected the primary mode of transportation each planned to use to get to school during the semester. The circle graph below shows the distribution of students who selected the various modes of transportation.      Registration for the second semester followed the same procedures. The number of students remained at 1,500, but the number who selected \"driving alone\" increased by 50 students. What fraction of the students selected \"driving alone\" for the second semester ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. In trapezoid ABCD, shown below with side lengths given in inches, AB is parallel to DC. What is the area of ABCD, in square inches ?", "choices": {"A": "24", "B": "40", "C": "48", "D": "72", "E": "96"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. The shaded figure below is a rectangle divided into 4 smaller rectangles. If h, i, j, and k are all different lengths and mark the lengths of line segments in the figure, in inches, which of the following expressions represents the area, in square inches, of the entire shaded figure?", "choices": {"A": "(h + i)(j + k)", "B": "2hk + 2ij", "C": "2(h + i) + 2(j + k)", "D": " hj + hk + hi + ik", "E": "hj + ij + hk + jk"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. Which of the following is equivalent to the expression 2x(x - 1)(x + 1) ? ", "choices": {"A": "4x3 - 4x", "B": "2x3 - 2", "C": "2x3 - 2x", "D": "2x2 - 2x", "E": "2x - 2"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, the coordinates of the midpoint of AB are (6, 8) and the coordinates of A are (3, 2). What are the coordinates of B ?", "choices": {"A": "(0, -4)", "B": "(3, 6)", "C": "", "D": "(9, 14)", "E": "(-3, -6)"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. The cost, C dollars, of hiring a taxi is given by the formula C = 2.00 +, where n is the number of tenths of a mile driven, What is the cost if the taxi is hired to drive 4.0 miles?", "choices": {"A": "$0.70", "B": "$2.60", "C": "$6.10", "D": "$8.00", "E": "$10.00"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. A surveyor is going to approximate the longest distance across Lake McLeland. She finds the approximate distances, in kilometers, and the approximate angle measures, in degrees, as shown in the figure below. If RT represents the longest distance across the lake, which of the following expressions approximates the length, in kilometers, of RT ?(Note: The law of cosines states that c2 = a2 + b2 - 2ab cos \u2220C, where a, b, and c are the lengths of the sides of any triangle and \u2220C is opposite the side of length c.)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. x3 \u00b7  is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "x3+2a", "C": "x6a", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. If f(x) = 2(x + 3) and g(x) = 4x - 4, what is the value of z such that f(z) = g(z) ?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "1", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. For all t, x, and w, -3tw2 + 6wt2x = ?", "choices": {"A": "3t2w2(-1 + 2x)", "B": "t2w2(-3 + 6x)", "C": "3tw (-w + 2tx)", "D": "2tw(-w + 2tx)", "E": "-3tw(w + 2tx)"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. In \u25b3ABC show below, AC = 4 inches and BC = 3 inches. What is cos A ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. The area of square ABCD below is 36 square centimeters. What is the perimeter of \u25b3ABD, in centimeters ?", "choices": {"A": "12 + ", "B": "", "C": "18", "D": "18 + ", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. Which of the following inequalities is equivalent to 4x - 1 \u2265 5x - 2 ?", "choices": {"A": "x \u2264 -3", "B": "x \u2265 -3", "C": "x \u2265 ", "D": "x \u2265 1", "E": "x \u2264 1"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. The row of squares below shows a pattern of 5 squares. This pattern repeats for 2,000 squares. Which of the following is the 1,821st square in this pattern ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. A circle has an area of 16\u03c0 square centimeters. What is the circumference of the circle, in centimeters ?", "choices": {"A": "4\u03c0", "B": "8\u03c0", "C": "16\u03c0", "D": "32\u03c0", "E": "256\u03c0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. The figure below shows a rectangular solid made up of small wooden cubes, each with an edge that measuresinch. What is the volume, in cubic inches, of the entire rectangular solid?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "9", "C": "18", "D": "24", "E": "72"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. In \u0394ABC below, D is on AB, E is on AC, DE is parallel to BC, and the lengths given are in inches. What is the length, in inches, of AE ?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46.  If \u2220A of parallelogram ABCD measures 40\u00b0 less than \u2220B measures, what is the degree measure of \u2220A ?", "choices": {"A": "60\u00b0", "B": "70\u00b0", "C": "80\u00b0", "D": "100\u00b0", "E": "110\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. For x \uff1e 2, ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. Which of the following statements is true of any integer satisfying 0 &lt; x &lt; 10 and (x-3)(x-6)(x-9) \u2260 0 ?", "choices": {"A": "x is odd.", "B": "x is even.", "C": "x is composite.", "D": "x is not divisible by 3.", "E": "x is not a perfect square."}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. Which of the following is the slope of a line in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane that is perpendicular to the line through (2, 4) and (5, 8) ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. In a 4-digit number, abcd, none of the digits (a, b, c, or d) is greater than 6. A new 4-digit number, wxyz, is to be constructed by keeping the digits in the same order as abcd and increasing exactly 2 of the digits. One digit is to be increased by 2, the other by 3. What is the smallest amount by which the new number can exceed the original number ?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "23", "C": "32", "D": "2,003", "E": "3,200"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. In \u0394ABC, \u2220B is a right angle, AB =  meters, BC = 30 meters, and CA = 100 meters, What is tan \u2220A ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. Right after graduating from college, Tim was offered a job. The job pays a starting salary of $30,000 per year. Tim computed what his salary would be each year for 10 years if he earned a 4% raise each year. The yearly salaries form a geometric sequence with what common ratio ?", "choices": {"A": "0.04", "B": "1.04", "C": "1.4", "D": "4", "E": "10"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. When A (4, 2) , shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below, is reflected across the line x = -2, what are the coordinates of its image?", "choices": {"A": "(-8, 2)", "B": "(-6, 2)", "C": "(-4, 2)", "D": "(4, -6)", "E": "(4, -2)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. Which of the following inequalities must be true for all possible values of x and y, if 2 &lt; x &lt; 3 and 3 &lt; y &lt;4 ?\u2160. x + y &lt; 7\u2161. y - x &lt; 1\u2162.", "choices": {"A": "\u2160 only", "B": "\u2160 and \u2161 only", "C": "\u2160 and \u2162 only", "D": "\u2161 and \u2162 only", "E": "\u2160, \u2161, and \u2162"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. For all x and y such that -2x + y = 1.5, when x is decreased by 2, y is:", "choices": {"A": "decreased by 4.", "B": "decreased by 2.", "C": "decreased by 1.", "D": "increased by 5.", "E": "increased by 6."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. To solve the equation x3 - 4x2 + x + 6 = 2x2 - 7x + 6, Bonita graphed the equations y = x3 - 4x2 + x + 6 and y = 2x2 - 7x + 6 in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, as shown below. What is the solution set of Bonita's original equation?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": "", "C": "\ufe5b-1, 2, 3\ufe5c", "D": "\ufe5b0, 2, 4\ufe5c", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. P and Q are two distinct planes, and P \u2229 Q is the set of points common to both P and Q. Which of the following could be P \u2229 Q ?I. No points at allII. A single pointIII. A single line", "choices": {"A": "\u2161 only", "B": "\u2160 and \u2161 only", "C": "\u2160 and \u2162 only", "D": "\u2161 and \u2162 only", "E": "\u2160, \u2161, and \u2162"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. A circle with a radius of 7 units is centered at the origin, as shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below. The circle is moved down 2 units on the y-axis. Which of the following are the x-intercepts of the new circle?", "choices": {"A": "-5 and 5", "B": "-9 and 9", "C": " and ", "D": " and ", "E": " and "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. A computer is programmed to accept a number, add 4 to it, and then multiply the sum by 5. If x represents the number first fed into the machine, and the result of the first run is then fed back into the computer, what will the result of the second run be ?", "choices": {"A": "5x + 40", "B": "5x + 120", "C": "25x + 40", "D": "25x + 104", "E": "25x + 120"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. For all \u03b1, which of the following expresses sin2 \u03b1 +3 cos \u03b1 - 1 in terms of cosines ?", "choices": {"A": "cos \u03b1", "B": "5 cos \u03b1 - 2", "C": "cos2\u03b1 + 3 cos \u03b1 - 2", "D": "cos2\u03b1 + 3 cos \u03b1", "E": "-cos2\u03b1 + 3 cos \u03b1"}, "correct": "E"}]}